Fabio Schettini ILGWU Publications 6036/102 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Fabio Schettini ILGWU Publications
1943-1988
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Schettini, Fabio, :International Ladies Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
6036/102 PUBS
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
This collection consists of various pamphlets documenting the ILGWU, the Liberal Party, and other New York unions that were collected by Fabio Schettini.
10377601
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
E. Parker, May 21, 2018
EAD encoding:
E. Parker, June 05, 2018
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Fabio Schettini was born in Brooklyn, New York on September 26, 1909. He earned his Bachelor of Science fron City College in 1943. Mr. Schettini joined ILGWU Local 48 in May 1944, where his mother-in-law was already a member. He worked as a business agent, price adjuster, and union organizer for the ILGWU. Mr. Schettini participated in the Mirror Coat Strike in 1949 and organized for the ILGWU in Bensonhurst neighborhood in Brooklyn.
According to his ILGWU autobiography (see Collection 5087/177, Box 2, Folder 30), he "learned [his] trade in Italy for four years and had [his] entire education in the evening schools of New York City. [He] was for 16 years a member of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America."
In 1964, he ran for New York State Assembly as the Liberal Party candidate, loosing to Democrat Noah Goldstein. In 1965, he ran for New York City Council as a Liberal Party candidate and campaigned for Republican John Lindsay's mayoral campaign.
Mr. Schettini was married to Antoinette Schettini. Together they had five children: Roland, Elaine, Linda, Nicholas, and Terry. His widow and children donated the materials in this collection.
Biographical / Historical
Local 48 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Italian Cloakmakers' Union, was chartered by members of Local 1 and Local 35 in 1916 and based in New York, New York. As membership and industry declined in the 1970s, the local became Local 48 United Coat, Suit and Allied Garment Workers' Union of Brooklyn, Queens and Staten Island (coat and suit workers in all crafts in Brooklyn, Queens and Staten Island), and later Local 48 Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers Union of North Brooklyn. In late 1981, the Joint Board approved a measure to dissolve Local 48, and Local 89 was renamed Local 89-48 to honor the historic significance of the Italian cloakmakers.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of pamphlets collected by Mr. Schettini during his time as a member of ILGWU Local 48. This includes convention proceedings as well as a history of the Northeast Department of the ILGWU. Of particular note is the pamphlet listing the rules and regulations for Local 48, which is printed in both Italian and English.
Also found in the collections are miscellaneous pamphlets. Of note among these pamphlets is the party platform for the Liberal Party's Municipal Plan, written for the New York City elections in 1949.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6036/102 P: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Photographs 6036/102 MB: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Memorabilia 6036/102m: Fabio Schettini ILGWU Files 5780/040: ILGWU Local 48 Records 5780/177: ILGWU Communications Department Biography Files
Clothing workers > Labor unions > United States.; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Schettini, Fabio; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 48 (New York, N.Y.); Liberal Party of New York State.
10377601
- ILGWU Constitutions and By-Laws. Local 48 Rules and Regulations, 1944-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Local 48 Rules and Regulations published in Italian and English.
  - Item 1: Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Marked copy. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). It is in English.
  - Item 3: Regolamento Interno Della Locale No. 48 I.L.G.W.U., Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) Local 48. Marked copy; Missing back cover and the front cover is completely detached from pamphlet. It is in English; Italian.
  - Item 4: Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Constitution anf By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1947; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Constitution and By-Laws of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Piece of newspaper between pages 36-37. It is in English.
- ILGWU 33rd Convention, Daily Proceedings and Proposed Amendments, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  May 1968
  - Item 1: Report of Proposed Amendments to the Constitution of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Recommended to the 33rd Convention by the Constitution Revision Committee of the General Executive Board, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). May 23, 1968. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Daily Proceedings 33rd Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Monday, May 27, 1968. It is in English.
- ILGWU 34th Convention, Daily Proceedings, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  May 1971
  - Item 1: Daily Proceedings 34th Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Friday, May 7, 1971. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Daily Proceedings 34th Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Monday, May 10, 1971. It is in English.
  - Item 3: Daily Proceedings 34th Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Tuesday, May 11, 1971 (1 of 2). It is in English.
  - Item 4: Daily Proceedings 34th Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By International Ladies' Garment Worker's Union (ILGWU). Tuesday, May 11, 1971 (2 of 2). It is in English.
  - Item 5: Daily Proceedings 34th Convention International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Wednesday, May 12, 1971. It is in English.
- "35 Years of the Northeast Department ILGWU, 1935-1970" by Harry Crone, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Distributed at ILGWU 34th Convention.
  - Item 1: 35 Northeast: a short history of the Northeast Department International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, AFL-CIO, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Harry Crone. It is in English.
  - Item 2: This Litle Gift Volume, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Sleeve for 35 Northeast, contains a quote from ILGWU President Stulberg and ILGWU Northeast emblem; marked on reverse. It is in English.
- ILGWU Benefit Pamphlets, 1943-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  (2 pamphlets)
  - Item 1: Rules and Regulations Retirement Fund of the Coat and Suit Industry in the New York Metropolitan Area, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU); Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc; Merchants' Ladies' Garment Association; Infants' and Childrens' Coat Assoiciation; American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association. June 1, 1943. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Health and Welfare Fund Dental Care Program, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Cloak Joint Board, ILGWU. It is in English.
- AFL-CIO Reports and Resolutions, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Labor Looks at the 91st Congress: an AFL-CIO Legislative Report, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations; AFL-CIO Department of Legislation. January 1971. It is in English.
  - Item 2: New York State AFL-CIO Resolutions Numbers 1 to 108, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By New York State AFL-CIO; American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. Marked copy. It is in English.
- New York City Pamphlets, 1949-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Agreement between New York, N.Y. Post Office, and National Association of Letter Carriers, Branch #36, National Postal Union, Manhatten-Bronx Postal Union, National Federation of Post Office Motor Vehicle Employees, Local #2, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By National Association of Letter Carriers, Branch #36, National Postal Union, Manhatten-Bronx Postal Union, National Federation of Post Office Motor Vehicle Employees, Local #2. March 8, 1970. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Rules Governing Drivers of Public Taxicabs and Public Coaches, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission. '1971' written in upper right corner of cover; on back cover 'Printing Section Polica Deaparment City of New York'. It is in English.
  - Item 3: For Our City: 1949 Municipal Program, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Liberal Party of New York State. It is in English.
  - Item 4: 66 Years of Democratic Education League for Industrial Democracy, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By League for Industrial Democracy. Conference pamphlet from June 5, 1971; most pages are advertisements for Unions presumably part of the League for Industrial Democracy. It is in English.
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1959-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Ideology and Co-Existence, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Moral Re-Armament. It is in English.
  - Item 2: Sweet Land of Liberty Four Americans Speak: Samual Goldwyn, Captain Eddie Rickenbacke, Charles Edison, Peter Pirogov, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Printed for the Union Carbide and Carbon Corporation. It is in English.
  - Item 3: Confidential Benefit Handbook, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Signature Agency Inc.; Legal Services Plan of America. Marked copy. It is in English.